<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-06T15:42:47+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">HagenDev</title><subtitle>A personal website and blog for Casey Hagen.</subtitle><author><name>Casey Hagen</name></author><entry><title type="html">Twenty Eighteen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/twenty-eighteen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twenty Eighteen" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/twenty-eighteen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/twenty-eighteen/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good-stuff&quot;&gt;The good stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of good times in 2018. To kick it off, our youngest son Evan was born. It was a tough road getting home after his birth, because myself, Elijah and Ethan all came down with the flu right after he was born. We were fortunate enough to have our Vegas family over here (two separate times!). We took a trip to visit family back in the states just in time for my niece’s first birthday, and I even made the transition to another position at work. I took six classes towards my Bachelor’s Degree in Healthcare Administration, maxing out my allowed Tuition Assistance. Towards the last half of the year, I took a deep dive into my habits and what I wanted to change about what I do each day, which leads to me to..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-not-so-good-stuff&quot;&gt;The not-so-good stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things that I set out to do, the stuff I wanted to accomplish.. Forget about it. I probably started out strong with coding, getting better at chess, reading more, implementing date nights, running more, riding my bike to work, saving money, not yelling at my kids.. but I know how I ended up: Not doing any of it. On one hand, it’s nice because I didn’t write anything down to make this feeling of disappointment in myself that I have worse. On the other hand, I’m beating myself up for not documenting at all. Looking back at it now, it looks like I hardly did anything that I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, the latter part of the year (starting November, really), I decided to take a break from FaceBook and really start to get to the bottom of why I can’t stick to what I say I’m going to do. I started reading more instead of playing video games and spending time with family instead of being glued to FaceBook all the time. I started to ramp up my blog back in November, and I think that helps with some of the stress. I even started taking home videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for tangible and measurable goals, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date night once per month&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read 10 books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bike to work at least once per week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run enough to earn my Harry Potter Running Club medals from 2017. Yes, from 2017.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mad-Eye Moody Constant Vigilance 5K&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hogwarts Running Club 9 3/4K&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sirius Black Half Marathon&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;(Here they are!)
&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/images/medals.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HRC Medals&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save least $500 for a starting emergency fund&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take more home videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog post twice a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the not-so-tangible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be more patient with your kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop being so broke all the time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to stay motivated and finish what you start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I guess that’s pretty much everything. I hope that 2019 isn’t a repeat of 2018. I’m thankful for my family and the people I am able to work with on a daily basis. I’m extremely lucky in that aspect to have such great and supportive people around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Casey Hagen</name></author><summary type="html">The good stuff I had a lot of good times in 2018. To kick it off, our youngest son Evan was born. It was a tough road getting home after his birth, because myself, Elijah and Ethan all came down with the flu right after he was born. We were fortunate enough to have our Vegas family over here (two separate times!). We took a trip to visit family back in the states just in time for my niece’s first birthday, and I even made the transition to another position at work. I took six classes towards my Bachelor’s Degree in Healthcare Administration, maxing out my allowed Tuition Assistance. Towards the last half of the year, I took a deep dive into my habits and what I wanted to change about what I do each day, which leads to me to.. The not-so-good stuff The things that I set out to do, the stuff I wanted to accomplish.. Forget about it. I probably started out strong with coding, getting better at chess, reading more, implementing date nights, running more, riding my bike to work, saving money, not yelling at my kids.. but I know how I ended up: Not doing any of it. On one hand, it’s nice because I didn’t write anything down to make this feeling of disappointment in myself that I have worse. On the other hand, I’m beating myself up for not documenting at all. Looking back at it now, it looks like I hardly did anything that I wanted to do. On the bright side, the latter part of the year (starting November, really), I decided to take a break from FaceBook and really start to get to the bottom of why I can’t stick to what I say I’m going to do. I started reading more instead of playing video games and spending time with family instead of being glued to FaceBook all the time. I started to ramp up my blog back in November, and I think that helps with some of the stress. I even started taking home videos. Looking forward As for tangible and measurable goals, here we go: Date night once per month Read 10 books Bike to work at least once per week Run enough to earn my Harry Potter Running Club medals from 2017. Yes, from 2017. Mad-Eye Moody Constant Vigilance 5K Hogwarts Running Club 9 3/4K Sirius Black Half Marathon (Here they are!) Save least $500 for a starting emergency fund Take more home videos Blog post twice a month For the not-so-tangible: Be more patient with your kids Stop being so broke all the time Learn how to stay motivated and finish what you start Well, I guess that’s pretty much everything. I hope that 2019 isn’t a repeat of 2018. I’m thankful for my family and the people I am able to work with on a daily basis. I’m extremely lucky in that aspect to have such great and supportive people around me. Thanks for reading!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Dig CSS Variables</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/why-i-dig-css-variables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Dig CSS Variables" /><published>2018-12-12T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-12-12T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/why-i-dig-css-variables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/why-i-dig-css-variables/">&lt;p&gt;I dig CSS variables. I had no idea such a cool thing existed before I came across them in FreeCodeCamp’s Responsive Web Design certification, but after refactoring the CSS for this site using them, I love it. I’ll admit, my admiration for CSS variables came entirely from my being extremely lazy to learn how to use SCSS with WordPress, but hey. It’s something new to me, and I enjoy it. Lets talk about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS variables can be extremely useful in reducing repetition in CSS, and in advanced cases, they can be used for cool effects like theme switching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;repetition-in-css&quot;&gt;Repetition in CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there. Repetition and clutter plague us all at some point, whether we like to admit it or not. Repeating color values is an example of CSS that is used constantly through a web page in order to keep styles consistent. The issue with repeating the color values in your CSS is that it’s potentially error-prone. Sure, you could “find and replace” all the things, but it could get dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-custom-properties-aka-custom-properties&quot;&gt;Enter Custom Properties, aka Custom Properties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are CSS variables in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:root&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#4ABDAC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--header-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#FFFFFF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--text-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#DFDCE3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--accent-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#F7B733&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;--background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;h4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;--header-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;font-family&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;'Open Sans'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, right? You define the variables in :root, which means they can be accessed throughout the entire document. Then, you call them when you need them with var(). Supes easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cascading-and-inheritance&quot;&gt;Cascading and Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as CSS is subject to cascading and inheritance, so are its custom properties. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;--acent-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:hover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:focus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--accent-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;@media&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min-width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;600px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;--accent-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;midnightblue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. And there you have it! By using the same custom property, we’re able to have different values in different places on the same page. Neato!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s my take on CSS variables and how I use them. I like the organizational aspect that comes with using them, and I know for a fact that there are a lot more use cases for them out there. Hoping to pick more of these up as I go, but it looks like I found a replacement for SCSS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the accompanying repo I made to go with this blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aechagen/css-variables&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Casey Hagen</name></author><summary type="html">I dig CSS variables. I had no idea such a cool thing existed before I came across them in FreeCodeCamp’s Responsive Web Design certification, but after refactoring the CSS for this site using them, I love it. I’ll admit, my admiration for CSS variables came entirely from my being extremely lazy to learn how to use SCSS with WordPress, but hey. It’s something new to me, and I enjoy it. Lets talk about it! CSS variables can be extremely useful in reducing repetition in CSS, and in advanced cases, they can be used for cool effects like theme switching. Repetition in CSS We’ve all been there. Repetition and clutter plague us all at some point, whether we like to admit it or not. Repeating color values is an example of CSS that is used constantly through a web page in order to keep styles consistent. The issue with repeating the color values in your CSS is that it’s potentially error-prone. Sure, you could “find and replace” all the things, but it could get dangerous. Enter Custom Properties, aka Custom Properties These are CSS variables in a nutshell: :root { --background-color: #4ABDAC; --header-color: #FFFFFF; --text-color: #DFDCE3; --accent-color: #F7B733; } body { background: var(--background-color); } h1,h2,h3,h4 { color: var(--header-color); font-family: 'Open Sans'; } Pretty simple, right? You define the variables in :root, which means they can be accessed throughout the entire document. Then, you call them when you need them with var(). Supes easy. Cascading and Inheritance Just as CSS is subject to cascading and inheritance, so are its custom properties. Check it out! a { color: var(--acent-color); } a:hover, a:focus { --accent-color: green; } @media (min-width: 600px) { a { --accent-color: midnightblue; } } .. And there you have it! By using the same custom property, we’re able to have different values in different places on the same page. Neato! Conclusion So that’s my take on CSS variables and how I use them. I like the organizational aspect that comes with using them, and I know for a fact that there are a lot more use cases for them out there. Hoping to pick more of these up as I go, but it looks like I found a replacement for SCSS Check out the accompanying repo I made to go with this blog post on Github</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Post - November 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/life-post-november-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Post - November 2018" /><published>2018-11-25T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/life-post-november-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/life-post-november-2018/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler alert:&lt;/em&gt; This a long-winded post about my life at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of a newly discovered favorite Youtuber Matt D’Avella, I decided to follow his lead and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9z8_YhWoq2o&quot;&gt;quit social media for 30 days&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of things led to this decision for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I invested way too much time with social media as a whole. Naturally, this takes me away from doing productive things.
When I browse social media, I fall into a “keeping up with the Joneses” phase with my peers, especially those in the Navy.
Nothing against those that recently commissioned as officers, or surpassed me in rank, or completed C-school to better themselves. This just caused me really take a deep dive in my thoughts and think about where I am now, and where I would like to be in the future. As of today, it has been 40 days since I quit Facebook and Instagram. Just for kicks, I decided to reinstall Facebook on my phone and see what it was like, fully expecting to be fully absorbed once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plot twist:&lt;/em&gt; I don’t think I’ll keep it on my phone longer than the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this past month has made me realize that the things that I focused on when I wasn’t aimlessly scrolling through my feeds are way more important. In the past month, I’ve focused on my school, bettering my habits and daily life choices, my relationship with my wife and my kids, and -pretty consistently for the past few days- rediscovering the newly recreated 3D version of Kanto in Pokemon Let’s Go Pikachu. On top of that, I’ve been reading more and listening to more audiobooks. On top of that, I even started coding and blogging, the latter of which I’ve been wanting to do for a while. (Wow, I’ve done a lot with my time this past month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on it all, I’m glad that I made that snap decision to disconnect from social media and reconnect with the things that really matter to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Casey Hagen</name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler alert: This a long-winded post about my life at this point. With the help of a newly discovered favorite Youtuber Matt D’Avella, I decided to follow his lead and quit social media for 30 days. A couple of things led to this decision for me: I invested way too much time with social media as a whole. Naturally, this takes me away from doing productive things. When I browse social media, I fall into a “keeping up with the Joneses” phase with my peers, especially those in the Navy. Nothing against those that recently commissioned as officers, or surpassed me in rank, or completed C-school to better themselves. This just caused me really take a deep dive in my thoughts and think about where I am now, and where I would like to be in the future. As of today, it has been 40 days since I quit Facebook and Instagram. Just for kicks, I decided to reinstall Facebook on my phone and see what it was like, fully expecting to be fully absorbed once again. Plot twist: I don’t think I’ll keep it on my phone longer than the weekend. The thing is, this past month has made me realize that the things that I focused on when I wasn’t aimlessly scrolling through my feeds are way more important. In the past month, I’ve focused on my school, bettering my habits and daily life choices, my relationship with my wife and my kids, and -pretty consistently for the past few days- rediscovering the newly recreated 3D version of Kanto in Pokemon Let’s Go Pikachu. On top of that, I’ve been reading more and listening to more audiobooks. On top of that, I even started coding and blogging, the latter of which I’ve been wanting to do for a while. (Wow, I’ve done a lot with my time this past month). Looking back on it all, I’m glad that I made that snap decision to disconnect from social media and reconnect with the things that really matter to me.</summary></entry></feed>